<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UCI blog - T.A.</title>
    <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UCI blog - T.A.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://adrientriquet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KNN</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/knn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:38:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/knn/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, the purpose was to train a KNN to recognise humour on faces.
In that purpose, we had a big database of 48*48 pixels pictures, and a start of a code on jupiter. It was the first time for me on this software and I found it really great, even as I am now used to google colab. Indeed, the capacity of doing it all in the machine is interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choregraphe</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/choregraphe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:51:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/choregraphe/</guid>
      <description>Structure :  The instalation The lab  Installation : so many options, so many fails If there is something I will remember about this lab, it will be : OH MY GOD HOW HARD WAS IT TO INSTALL CHOREGRAPH. Here are the different tests I did in order to use the choregraphe application.
The macbook application Two students, including me, were using macOS. We both had the same issue : the application simply did not launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 16:46:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Welcome here, I am Adrien Triquet.   I am a last year engineering student at Telecom SudParis. I am currently studying image processing, with work in artificial intelligence and deep learning. In addition, I am attending a second diploma, a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from the Polytechnic Institute of Paris in virtual and augmented reality.
  What is the purpose of this blog ?   This blog is meant to group all my works for my master among the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First lecture</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:48:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai/</guid>
      <description>In progress</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First lecture</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:48:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/blender/</guid>
      <description>Structure :   The rocket
  The car
  The character
  A first touch with a rocket   Actually, it was not my very first time on blender as I already learned how to do a few things on my free time. Indeed, mostly interested by software like Final Cut or the Adobe suite (Premiere, Photoshop and lightroom most of all). Blender was another tool I had to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First lecture</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:48:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/unity/</guid>
      <description>Structure :  Introduction Game design Design The character Scripts Difficulties Demo  The purpose of this class was to build our first platformer by our own. We had been really free on the content and game design and it was such a pleaser as I never used Unity before.
  The game design   The first platform I started by the game design, experimenting different tools. I began with a simple platform with walls that hide the success area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
