<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UCI blog - T.A.</title>
    <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UCI blog - T.A.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://adrientriquet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 16:26:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/opencv/</guid>
      <description>This class aimed to show things possible with the OpenCv library on Python.
Of course, I already used it several time to work on pictures or videos.
Moreover, I know already the OpenPose library after a project of movement recognition about it.
For the lab part, it has been more than complex :
 The 3D reconstruction never works because of different paths issues I never succeded to solve. However I was able to try it and to see with over students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 10:44:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/3d/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this lab, we want to practice the reconstruction of a 3D object thanks to pictures (2D).
My work I decided to pic my bear I use as keychain. I took 19 pictures of it on a white support. I used as many light as possible even if the natural light was not great as the weather was really cloudy.
It began wrong as I had this message :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurrent neural network</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 16:35:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/rnn/</guid>
      <description>Colab link Here you can find all my code : https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1Ott9Odhu1P6uQP186DWs3ApiEGlzC21i#scrollTo=DvwJIcmOKjOQ
Introduction After several classes and personal work on CNN which analyse on data after another, this class presents RNN which will enable to analyse for instance a video as such, not simply as several frames. Indeed, RNN can learn on sequential database.
It is used du to limitation of the FFNN (Feed Forward Neural Network) which could only use fixed size windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 14:12:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/rl/</guid>
      <description>Colab link Here you can find all my code : https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1KHNH1-sgeiHZoaU9Gn2laJl_o-Y3d1z7
Introduction After one class about reinforcement learning, this lab purpose is to implement a method to resolve the &amp;ldquo;Cart pole&amp;rdquo; problem.
Note that a real RL application would use a framework with most of the tools, here we want to understand how it really works.
Theory As a reminder, reinforcement learning is a teaching by experience. We test different actions and see what happens then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats / dogs recognition</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 11:30:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai3/</guid>
      <description>Repo link Here you can find all my code : https://github.com/AdrienTriquet/AI3
Moreover, here you can find all the different models I used and saved : https://drive.google.com/file/d/1loBwiJ8QRxWXTxz5hhJ7p15csJfEFJNF/view?usp=sharing
Introduction This lab aims to implement many different neural networks to see their different results. Let&amp;rsquo;s make my computer melt !
First, here is a look at the data used :
Different models   A first CNN   A first simple CNN with two convuloutional layers gave me 74 % of accuracy after testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashion MINST</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 11:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai2/</guid>
      <description>Repo link Here you can find all my code : https://github.com/AdrienTriquet/IA2
Introduction This lab is a classic to begin using CNN and tensorflow : the MINST fashion recognition. It is a little more complex than the digit one.
Once again, let&amp;rsquo;s see the impact of different parameters in this new CNN.
Note : you better have a good computer to compute all those network. It can take very long.
Parameters   Number of filters   For 5 epochs I got :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AND / OR / XOR gates</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:54:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai0/</guid>
      <description>Repo link Here you can find all my code : https://github.com/AdrienTriquet/IA0
Introduction This lab had for purpose to give us a first overview of Artificial Intelligence and to create a same work environment for all.
Being a user of Pycharm already, I did not have to prepare anything. I already work on a good virtual environment on Python 3.8.
First application At first, we used an ANN (artificial neuron network) to learn the AND gate output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digit MINST</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 15:58:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/ai1/</guid>
      <description>Repo link Here you can find all my code : https://github.com/AdrienTriquet/IA1
Introduction This lab is a classic to begin using CNN and tensorflow : the MINST digit recognition.
After the build of the network, our purpose was to see the impact of different parameters in the results and to of course understand why.
The parameters   Number of neurons   Here are the results for 5 epochs and the batch size equal to 32 to determine the impact of the number of neurons in the input dense layer :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNN</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/knn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 14:38:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/knn/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, the purpose was to train a KNN to recognise humour on faces.
In that purpose, we had a big database of 48*48 pixels pictures, and a start of a code on jupiter. It was the first time for me on this software and I found it really great, even as I am now used to google colab. Indeed, the capacity of doing it all in the machine is interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choregraphe</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/choregraphe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:51:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/choregraphe/</guid>
      <description>Structure :  The instalation The lab  Installation : so many options, so many fails If there is something I will remember about this lab, it will be : OH MY GOD HOW HARD WAS IT TO INSTALL CHOREGRAPH. Here are the different tests I did in order to use the choregraphe application.
The macbook application Two students, including me, were using macOS. We both had the same issue : the application simply did not launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 16:46:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Welcome here, I am Adrien Triquet.   I am a last year engineering student at Telecom SudParis. I am currently studying image processing, with work in artificial intelligence and deep learning. In addition, I am attending a second diploma, a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from the Polytechnic Institute of Paris in virtual and augmented reality.
  What is the purpose of this blog ?   This blog is meant to group all my works for my master among the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender teaching</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:48:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/blender/</guid>
      <description>Structure :   The rocket
  The car
  The character
  A first touch with a rocket   Actually, it was not my very first time on blender as I already learned how to do a few things on my free time. Indeed, mostly interested by software like Final Cut or the Adobe suite (Premiere, Photoshop and lightroom most of all). Blender was another tool I had to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity teaching</title>
      <link>https://adrientriquet.github.io/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 14:48:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adrientriquet.github.io/unity/</guid>
      <description>Structure :  Introduction Game design Design The character Scripts Difficulties Demo  The purpose of this class was to build our first platformer by our own. We had been really free on the content and game design and it was such a pleaser as I never used Unity before.
  The game design   The first platform I started by the game design, experimenting different tools. I began with a simple platform with walls that hide the success area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
